RAHUL LOKHANDE

PRODUCT MANAGER

Key Skills

- Requirement Gathering
- Product Owner
- Product Management
- Agile
- Product Planning
- Scrum
- Agile Methodology
- Requirement Analysis
- Payments
- Fintech
- Payment Processing
- Merchant Acquiring
- US Healthcare
- ERP
- Business Analysis
- Product Manager
- Bfsi

Certification

- SAFe 5.0 PO PM
- SAFe Agilist Certification Workshop

PHONE I (+91) 9827635576

EMAIL I rahullokhande0510@gma

il.com

LOCATION I Indore, INDIA

EXPERIENCE I 14 Years O Month

Profile Summary

Working as a Product Manager with a Fortune 20 firm with 14 years of experience in Product management, Business Analysis/Consulting with onsite experience in USA and Europe. Working on Customer Experience domain and have extensive experience on Payment domain, USA healthcare and benefits, USA life science compliance and e-comm ERP solutions. I have a valid B1/B2 VISA. Looking for a challenging opportunity as Sr. Product Manager/Assistant Director

Work Experience

Product Manager

Verizon

08/2021 - Present

* Driving the initiatives for CX improvement for product development * Idealizing and formulation of product strategies * User Stories and acceptance criteria writing * Product enhancement

Lead Product Owner

FIS

07/2018 - 07/2021

??? Working as Product Owner for both POS and ecommerce products ??? Responsible for collaborating with the product group on product vision, strategy and roadmap, feature refinements and prioritization using MoSCoW and preliminary estimates ??? Translated features into user stories within the team???s backlog while managing, ranking, and prioritizing this backlog to reflect stakeholder???s requirements ??? Responsible for conducting workshops with Product Manager, Solution architects, development teams and various

 Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

Languages

- English
- Hindi

Social links

 linkedin.com/in/rahullokhande-pm

internal/external stakeholders to elicit requirements and derive optimum solution ??? Responsible for creating user story maps, flow diagrams, AS-IS and TO-BE processes and wireframes using MS Visio ??? Experience of working in US, UK, European & Australian geographies. ??? Drive and own the SAFE ceremonies as Refining, Sprint review and Demo, participate actively in Retro and Planning ??? Write User stories and acceptance criteria for team to understand the requirement better ??? Work closely with the UK and USA business team for requirement gathering and share with the agile development team ??? Articulated product vision and user stories in a way clearly understandable to development teams. ??? Managed backlog of user stories for 2 products simultaneously. ??? Working knowledge of acquirer integration, payment gateway, scheme specifications, accreditation, ISO 8583 communications transaction and admin messages, P2PE, EMV and payment processing, 3DSecure and stored credentials ??? Stakeholder management and client management

Senior Business Analyst

InfoBeans 07/2017 - 07/2018

??? Played a crucial role in SCRUM Transformation and building a team of Product Owners from scratch ??? Conducted requirement gathering workshops with the clients ??? Managed Solution Scope and Requirements ??? obtain consensus among stakeholders regarding overall solution scope and requirements to be implemented ??? Prepared SOW, functional & system requirement documents ??? Requirement elicitation and documentation as BRDs ??? Project governance and defining quality metrics ??? Drafting user stories and acceptance criteria ??? Responsible for defect creation, tracking and retesting in JIRA ??? Test case preparation and execution

Business Analyst

ValueLabs

??? Worked onsite at Charleston, South Carolina during the peak Open Enrollment period as a Business Analyst ??? Requirement gathering through discovery calls with each customer for their customized life and health plans ??? Worked in a hybrid role of quality analyst and business analyst ???

Perform testing and UAT for every integration ???
Report defects using JIRA and retesting them once they were fixed ??? Setup a Connsys/Auto transmission protocol for Delivery tenant setup ???
Co-ordinated and prioritized project tasks, managed timelines, tracked delivery status and communicated status to clients and senior management. ??? A Certified Payroll analyst dealing in demographic and deduction files, as a Certified EDI Analyst develop EDI files with benefit details to carrier

Senior Business Analyst

HotWax Systems

??? Design the flow of the application and design the screens ??? Designing wireframes and mock-up using tools such as Balsamiq and Axure RP Pro ??? Design all the frames and mock-ups for the applications ??? Create the SRS for the complete application including UML diagrams ??? Create Test plan including test cases and test scenarios ??? Sprint planning and milestones designing ??? Creating product backlog ??? Perform UAT and help with testing scenarios

Senior Executive

Impetus Technologies 05/2013 - 04/2014

??? Worked closely with Technical architect and managers to draft the requirements ??? Understand the client requirement and transfer the knowledge to the dev team ??? Deliver demo to the prospects via WebEx ??? For BI tool, Performance testing tool ??? Client calls to discuss the requirements for custom Big Data solution ??? Create the presentations and deck for client presentations

Assistant Manager

Webdunia

??? Client account management ??? Presales activities and deliver demos to the client ??? Create the presentations and deck for client presentations ??? Understand the requirement and draft the initial plan for go to market strategies ??? Draft high-level requirement for the teams ??? Schedule and deliver demos

Education

MBA/PGDM - Operations

2010

Vinayaka Mission University (VMU)

Grade - 9/10

B.Tech/B.E. - Electronics/Telecommunication 2007

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya (RGPV), Bhopal

Grade - 64.31%

12th

2002

Madhya Pradesh , English Grade - 60-64.9%

10th

2000

Madhya Pradesh , English Grade - 75-79.9%

Projects

Life and health insurance

-736271 Days

It is one of the top notch SaaS based US organizations that provides life and healthcare benefits to multiple customers across USA.